

Adnan Zaman



adnanzaman570@gmail.com



+923059393451

Languages

- English
- Urdu
- Pushto

Interest

- Cricket
- Travelling
- Reading

SUMMARY

A confident and motivated Professional Tester with experience in software testing/ quality assurance and a complete understanding of software development, working on projects including E-Commerce, Business Application and Web Application an effective team player, willingness to learn and self-starter.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Software Testing (Websites and Mobile Apps)
- **Testing**: Functional, Cross browser, System, Smoke, Sanity Regression and Exploratory Testing.
- Life cycles/methodologies: Sequential (V-model, Waterfall), Agile (Scrum)
- **Test documentation**: Test case creation, Test execution and daily/weekly progress reports.
- Tools: Jira, Slack, Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

December 2022 – Present SMSAMI

ROLE: SOFTWARE QUALTIY ASSURANCE ENGINEER

SMSAMI is a USA based Company and one of its branches is currently working in Pakistan. My roles and responsibilities as a software test analyst are as follows.

- Worked on POS, Ready to munch projects
- Worked closely with Developers and business analyst while testing the POS & RTM.
- Plan, written and executed manual test script using JIRA. Also logged defects in JIRA.
- Involved in daily team meetings, Backlog grooming and planning as well.
- Followed strict agile methodologies while working at SMSAMI.

June 2022 – December 2022 Aartec Imagination Delivered

ROLE: SOFTWARE TEST ANALYST

Aartec is a UK based Company and one of its branches is currently working in Pakistan. My roles and responsibilities as a software test analyst are as follows.

- Functional Testing of Web Applications
- Requirement Reviews/ Clarification
- Test Cases Creation
- Bug Reporting
- Test Result Reports Creation
- Regression Testing
- Design Testing

EDUCATION

Feb 2017 - Dec 2021 Sukkur IBA University, Sukkur

BSc Software Engineering

CERTIFICATES

- Certified ISTQB CTFL Tester.
- Certified in TEFL
- Certified in Speaking English Professionally, coursera 2020
- Position Holder in Book Review Competition, SUKKUR IBA UNIVERSITY 2017.
- Certified in Data Structures and Algorithm's
- Certified in HTML, CSS and JAVASCRIPT
- Certified in Mobile Android Development

ACHIEVEMENTS

- National Talent Hunt Program (NTHP) fully funded Scholarship Winner 2016, at SUKKUR IBA UNIVERSITY
- Winners at Sports Gala 2022, Sukkur IBA University
- Executive in Sports and Adventurous Society 2017, Sukkur IBA University
- Runners up in Cricket at LUMS University 2019, Lahore